Guide to the William Arthur Rawlins papers, 1930-1972.
Rawlins, William Arthur papers, 1930-1972.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William Arthur Rawlins papers, 1930-1972.
21-23-1775
William Arthur, Rawlins 1908-
8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, data books, radio talks, handbooks, course material, papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers include general correspondence, and correspondence and reports from Rawlins' work with the Food and Agricultural Organization's Mission to Poland and with the Ford Foundation in India.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Entomologist; professor of entomology, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include general correspondence (1930-1972), and correspondence and general reports from Rawlins' work with the Food and Agricultural Organization's Mission to Poland (1947, 1951-1952), and with the Ford Foundation in India (1967-1970); reports, the majority on potato disease, lettuce yellows, aster yellows and carrot rust fly control; data books recording the progress of various potato experiments (1937-1958); county agents' school reports; and miscellaneous radio talks, senate testimony, handbooks, and course material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rawlins, William Arthur, 1908-; Cornell University--Faculty.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations. Mission to Poland.; Ford Foundation.
Subjects:
Agriculture.; Agricultural pests.; Plant diseases.; Entomology.; Agriculture--Poland.; Entomologists.; College teachers.
Places:
India.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Subseries A. 1930-1972
    - 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - 1945 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - 1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
    - 1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1949 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1950 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    - 1952 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - 1953 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
    - 1954 (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
    - 1955 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
    - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - 1958 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
    - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7-9)
    - 1960 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
    - 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
    - 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
    - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B. International projects
    - Polish Mission, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Maps of Poland (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - FAO Field Reports, Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - "Reprints" - Correspondence related to Dailp Gupta's, "Persistence of Two Systematic Carbamate Insecticides in three types of soils", 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Indian Correspondence" (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Reprints and Publications, related correspondence (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - India - Ford Foundation Material, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report Research on the insect pests of Maize with special reference to stalk borders, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series II. Reports
  - Subseries A. Potato Scab, 1930's
    - Blodgett, F.M., "Progress Report on Potato Disease Investigations", June 1935-Apr. 1937 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "Progress Report on Potato Diseases. Investigations during Summer 1937" (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Burke, O.D., "A Contribution to the Knowledge of the Life History of the Colorado Potato Beetle under Long Island Conditions" (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Potato Spraying Experiments at Riverhead, 1930-1931" (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Potato Spraying Experiments, Riverhead, Long Island, New York, 1930" (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Cowan, E.K., "Potato Seed Treatments and Related Experiments in Wyoming County" (with L.L. Stirland and F.M. Blodgett), 1938 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Cowan, E.K., "Results of Potato Seed Treatment Experiments in Wyoming County, New York", 1934 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Cowan, E.K., "Results of Seed Treatment Experiments in Wyoming and Genesee Counties", 1935 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Cowan, E.K., "Experimental Results Varying Concentrations of Yellow Oxide Seed Treatment - Wyoming County" (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Cowan, E.K., "Results of Potato Seed Treatment Experiments in Wyoming, Genesee and Madison Counties, 1936" (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Cowan, E.K., "Results of Potato Seed Treatment Experiments in Wyoming, Erie, Oneida, and Madison Counties", 1937 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Decker, Plares, "Potato Scab Control in Western New York", 1938 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Dickinson, William, "Notes for 1934" (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Dickinson, William, "Potato Spraying and Dusting in Nassau County, Long Island" (with G.F. MacLeod) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Dickinson, William, Flea Beetle Experiment;" "Potato Spraying Experiemtns at Hicksville, 1933;" Misc. untitled (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Epps, W.M., "Potato Spray and Dust Experiments in Wyoming County, New York, 1938;" "Potato Spray and Dust Experiments in Wyoming County, New York, 1939", 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Findlen, P.J., "Some Facts Concerning Consumer and Retailer Demand for Potatoes in Cleveland, Ohio", Apr. 14, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Findlen, P.J., "A Summary of Facts Relating to Consumer and Retailer Demand and Preference for Potatoes", 1939 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Kelly, Keith and Erickson, Ralph, "Report of Investigations on Plant Growth Stimulation by Mixtures of Ground Pyrethrum Flowers and Oils", 1938 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - McCormick, R.B., "Potato Spraying Experiments at Sagaponack, N.Y.", 1930-1932 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - McCubben, E.N., "Report on Potato Rotation Project, Steuben County", 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - MacLeod, G.J., "Progress Report of Experiments with Potato Insects", Apr. 14, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Mader, E.O., "Potato Spraying and Dusting Experiments" (with F.M. Blodgett and C.J. Taylor), 1929 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Mader, E.O., "Potato Spraying and Dusting Experiments at Pittsford, N.Y.", 1929-1931; 1934 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Mader, E.O., "A Report of the Results of Spraying and Dusting Experiments at Pittsford from 1929-1932", Jan. 4, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Mader, E.O., "Potato Spraying Experiments a Gainsville, N.Y.", 1935 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Maughn, Frank B., "Varietal Differences in Insect Populations and Injuries to Potatoes" (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Menusan, H. Jr., "Results of Potato Dusting Experiments on Organic Soils" (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Menusan, H. Jr., "Potato Spraying and Dusting Experiments on Long Island" (with Wm. Dickinson) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Menusan, H. Jr., "Report on Potato Spraying, Central Park, Long Island, 1931", 1932 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Menusan, H. Jr., "Preliminary Report, Potato Spray Experiments at Central Park, L.I.", Oct. 1932 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Nash, K.B., "Report of the Potato Rotation Project in Franklin County 1936-1937", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Nash, K.B., "Temporary Report of the Potato Rotation Project in Franklin County", 1937 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Nash, K.B., "Investigation of the Potato Rotation Project in Franklin County", 1938 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Nottingham, J.O., "Preliminary Report on Spraying and Dusting Experiments in Nassau County, Long Island", 1937 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Nottingham, J.O., "Preliminary Report - 1937 Dusting and Spraying Experiments on Potatos in Hicksville Area" (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Nottingham, J.O., "Investigations of Potato Insects in Nassau County during 1938" (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Nottingham, J.O., "Report of Spraying and Dusting Experiments on Potatoes in Nassau County", 1939 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Nottingham, J.O., "Report on Potato Experiments in Nassau County", 1940 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Peterson, L.C., "Potato Spraying Experiments Conducted at Sagaponack and Water Mill, Long Island, N.Y.", 1936 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Peterson, L.C., "Resume of Potato Spraying Experiments Conducted at Sagaponack, Suffolk County, Long Island, N.Y. in 1937", 1938 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Three appendices (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Rawlins, W.A., Misc. Reports and Studies of Potato Defects in Western N.Y.; Thesis; "Biology and Control of the Wheat Wireworm" (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Roney, James N., "Report of the Muckland Potato Dusting Experiments in Genesee and Orleans Counties", 1939 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Simpson, G.W., "Potato Spraying Experiment", 1930 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Simpson, G.W., "Report of Potato Investigations at Hicksville, L.I." (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Simpson, G.W., "Potato Spraying and Dusting Experiments...Hicksville, L.I.", 1930 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Skaptason, J.B., "Potato Spraying Experiments in Suffolk County, N.Y.", 1937 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Smith, Ora, "Some Factors which Influence Interior Quality of Potatoes", 1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Stafford, Eugene M., "Report of Summer Work in Wayne County", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Stirland, L.L., "Potato Seed Treatment Tests", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Stirland, L.L., "Progress Report of the Potato Tuber Injury Investigation" (with W.A. Rawlins), 1930 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Taylor, C.J., "A Preliminary Report on Potato Scab Control in Western N.Y.", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "The Second [Third, Fourth, Fifth, and Sixth] Report on Potato Scab Control in Western N.Y." (with addenda), 1932-1935; 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Tuthill, C.S., "The Potato Rotation Project in Genesee County, 1936", 1937-1941 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Udey, E.C., "Potato Spraying Experiments in Wyoming County", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Misc. unlabeled or untitled, 1930-1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B. Reports, 1940-1945
    - Ashdown, David, "Investigations of the Control of Lettuce Yellows through Control of the Aster Leafhopper", 1943 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Bradfield, R. and Mustgrave, R.B., "Summaries of the Yields of all Crops Grown in the Potato Rotation Experiment in Franklin, Genesee, and Steuben Counties for the first Five-Year Period", 1936-1940 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Dewey, James E., "Report: Results and Observations of Potato Control Projects on Long Island", 1943 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Erickson, Ralph, "Report of Investigations on Plant Growth Stimulation by Mixtures of Derris, Pyrethrum Flowers, and Oils", 1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Erickson, Ralph, "Spraying for Control of Potato Insects, Erie County", 1942 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Gyrisco, George Gordon, "Potato Insecticide Experiments, Suffolk County", 1945 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Jodka, Jospeh F.T., "Report: Potato Spraying Experiments, Erie County", 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - McGoldrick, Fred, "Report on Potato Rotation Project, Steuben County", 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Miner, F.D., "Summary of Muckland Potato Dusting Experiments", 1941 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Olson, Robert E., "Investigations of the Eastern Field Wireworm, Limonius ectypus, Say.", 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Olson, Robert E., "Potato Rotation Project, Monroe County", 1942 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Pratt, John Jr., "Potato Spraying Experiments, Erie County", 1941 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Rawlins, W.A., "Summary of Potato Insect Pest Investigations on Long Island" (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Roney, James Neville, "The Potato Leafhopper Empoasca fabae Harris and its injury to Muckland Potatoes" (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Roney, James Neville, "Muckland Potato Dusting Experiments", 1940 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Roth, Roger W., "Potato Insect Spray and Dust Experiments in Nassau County", 1942 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Skaptason, J.B., "Test of Material for Flea Beetle Control", 1939 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Skaptason, J.B., "Preliminary Report on Potato Spray and Dusting Experiments on Long Island", 1940 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Skaptason, J.B., "Potato Spraying Experiments in Suffolk County, N.Y.", 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "Final Yield of Green Mountain Potatoes...at Riverhead, L.I.", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "Counts of Early Blight Lesion and Final Yield on Green Mountain Potatoes", 1941 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Smith, Wilson and Wilkinson, Robert E., "Progress Report on Testing Scab Resistant Seedlings", 1946 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Smith, Wilson and Wilkinson, Robert E., "Report on the Potato Rotation Project in Genesee County", 1944 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Staples, Robert and Cotton, Robert, "Potato Spray and Dust" (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Staples, Rawlins and Cotton, Robert, "Report on Potato Spraying Experiments", 1940 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Thomas, Charles A., "Report on the Potato Rotation Project in Genesee County", 1943 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Thomas, Charles A., "Report on a Supplementary Rotation Experiment...Genesee County, N.Y.", 1943 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Wene, George, "Potato Insecticide Experiments in Monroe County", 1945 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Wene, George, "Report, Monroe County Potato Rotation Project", 1941; 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Wright, C.M., "Potato Spraying Experiments in Suffolk County, Long Island, N.Y.", 1945 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Wright, C.M., "Some Potato Spraying Experiments Conducted on the South Fork, Long Island, N.Y.", 1945 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Misc. and untitled or unidentified reports (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Subseries C. Reports, 1945-1950
    - Ashdown, Donald, "Studies of Onion Thrips", 1947 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Belkin, John, "Report on Foliage Injury Test Plant Sprays" (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Bliss, C.I., "Outline of Lectures on Statistical Methods in Entomological Research" (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Cetas, Robert C., "Potato Spraying Experiments in the Bridgehampton Area of Suffolk County", 1947; 1950 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Davis, A.C. and Rawlins, W.A., "Recent Progress in the Control of Wireworms on Potatoes", 1947 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Ewart, W.H., "Report on Field Work on Muckland Vegetable Crops in Orange County, N.Y. for the summer of 1947" (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - French, Alex M., "Western N.Y. Potato Spray Experiments", 1947; 1949 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - French, Alex M., "Potato Dust Experiment", 1946 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - French, Alex M., "Potato Spray and Dust Experiments", 1946 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Kirk, Vernon M., "Potato Insecticide Experiments in Suffolk County, Long Island, N.Y.", 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Leiby, R.W., "An Evaluation of Bean Beetle Control on Dry Beans", 1949 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Leiby, R.W., "Bean Neetle Control on Dry Beans", 1950 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Leiby, R.W., "Potato Insect Control...", 1947 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Leiby, R.W., "Summary of Tests on Vegetable Insect Control", 1946 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Meklenbacher, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Menusan, H, Jr., "Results of Potato Dusting Experiments on Organic Soils" (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Menusan, H, Jr., "Potato Spraying and Dusting Experiments on Muckland", 1931-1934 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Menusan, H, Jr., "Size of Plot and Its Relationship to Field Spraying Experiments with Potatoes" (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - "Muckland Potato Reports" (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Post, Richard L.; McCalley, Russell W.; and Munro, J. Alex, "Insecticidal Application and Potato Yields in North Dakota", 1949 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Rawlins, W.A., "Potato Insect Control" (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Rawlins, W.A.; Wene, George P.; Gyrisko, George and Jodka, Joseph; "Report of laboratory and greenhouse studies pertaining to problems of potato insect control" (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Rawlins, William A., Thesis - "Biology and Control of Wheat Wireworm in Western N.Y." (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Roth, Roger W. and Gyrisco, Gorge Gordon, "Potato Insecticide Experiments in Suffolk and Nassau Counties, Long Island, N.Y.", 1946 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Ruehle, George D., "Recent Spray Tests for Control of Potao Late Blight in Sub-Tropical Florida" (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Sloan, M.J., "Studies on Lettuce Yellows, Onion Maggot, and Onion Thrips;" "Summary of Year's Work", 1948 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Stafford, Eugene M., "Report of Work Done in Wayne County, 1938;" "Report of Summer Work for 1937", 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Staples, Rovert, "Potato Insecticide Experiments in Monroe County, N.Y.", 1946 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Strong, Rudolph G., "1964 Experiments Concerning the Prevention of Aster Yellow Virus Disease in Lettuce" (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sun, Yun-Pei, "A Preliminary Study of the Influence of Velisicol AR-60 upon the Insecticidal Effectiveness of Dusts Containing Rotenone or DDT", 1946 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Misc. and unlabeled (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - Subseries D. Lettuce yellows reports
    - Ashdown, Donald, "Investigations of the Control of Lettuce Yellows through the Control of the Aster Leafhopper" (Bankhead-Jones Project 50), 1942-1943; 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Bacon, "Muckland Insect Investigations, Lettuce Yellows", 1952 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Ewart, W.H., "Investigations of the Control of Lettuce Yellows through the Control of the Aster Leafhopper", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Notebook, D. Gonzalez, Savannah Lettuce Plots, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Roney, J.N., "Report of Investigations of Lettuce Yellows and Experiments for Control of the Aster Leafhopper Conducted on the Elba Muckland, Summer 1939", 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sloan, M.J., "Studies on Lettuce Yellows, Onion Maggot, and Onion Thrips. Oswego Co." Report and notes, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Reports on Projects Bankhead-Jones 50 and 56;" "Lettuce Yellows Experimentsfor 1948" (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "Muckland Insect Investigations", 1950 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Muckland Insect Investigations", 1951 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Strong, Rudolph G., "Aster Yellows Transitions Experiments;" "Muckland Lettuce Pest Investigations for 1953" (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Aster Yellows Transmissions Experiments. Notebook #2." Experiment 3D (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - "Lettuce Experiments, Summer 1954" (Notebook) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "1954 Experiments Concerning the Prevention of Aster Yellows Virus Disease in Lettuce" (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Aster Yellows Transitions Experiments" Notebook #1, #3 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Insecticide Experiments, Notebooks #1 and #2, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Thompson, Leith S., "1958 Experiments Concerning Prevention of Aster Yellows Virus Disease..." Summer Report (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Thompson, Leith S., "1959 Studies of Aster Yellows and Its Vector, the Six-Spotted Leafhopper" (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Thompson, Leith S., "1960 Summer Report. 'Aster-Yellows and the Six-Spotted Leafhopper'" (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Subseries E. Carrot rust fly reports
    - Unknown. "Carrot Rust Fly Experiments in 1951", 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "Preliminary Trials to Control the Carrot Rust Fly" (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "Carrot Rust Fly Experiments, Summer 1952. Spray Treatment for Second Brood Maggots" (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Harris, Emmet D. Jr., "Summer Report for 1952," Carrot Insect Investigations, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - "Report of Carrot Rust Fly Investigations", 1955 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Reports (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Project Reports, 1935-1960 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Subseries F. Onion maggots
    - Project Reports (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Series III. Data books
  - Wormwire Project B.J. 32, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Wormwire Project, 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Western New York Potato Spraying Projects, 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Muckland Potato Dusting Project, 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Cotton, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 1945 Potato Experiments, Suffolk County by George G. Gyrisko (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1945 Potato Project, Suffolk County, George G. Gyrisko (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Watkins, Thomas C. and Norton, L.B., "Properties and Commercial Sources of Insecticide Dust Diluents and Carriers", Feb. 1947 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Muckland Potato Project, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - "Abstracts of the Chlordane, Endrin, and Heptachlor Literature", Nov. 1954-1958 (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
  - Heptachlor Formulator's Manual (Box 8, Folder 20-21)
- Series IV. Miscellany
  - Subseries A. County agents school reports
    - 1932-1933, 1935-1936, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - 1941 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - 1942 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - 1943 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1944 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 1945 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1947 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1950 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B. Congress of crop protection, 1957
    - Books and programs (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Folder contents (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Subseries C. Radio Talks, 1931-1951
    - Radio Talks, 1931-1951 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Subseries D. Course material
    - Entomology 12 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Class Reports on Insecticides (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Subseries E. Testimony
    - Copy of testimony to be presented at the hearings of the Food and Drug Administration on insecticide residues (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Subseries F. Miscellany
    - Potato Committee Meeting, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Handbook for Operators of Potato Spray Rings, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Fumigation Plots on Muck, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 18)